(this["webpackJsonpreact-flashcard-app"]=this["webpackJsonpreact-flashcard-app"]||[]).push([[0],{12:function(e,a,t){},13:function(e,a,t){"use strict";t.r(a);var s=t(0),n=t.n(s),o=t(5),i=t.n(o),r=t(6),c=t(1);function l(e){var a=e.flashcard,t=Object(s.useState)(!1),o=Object(c.a)(t,2),i=o[0],r=o[1],l=Object(s.useState)("initial"),u=Object(c.a)(l,2),d=u[0],m=u[1],h=Object(s.useRef)(),p=Object(s.useRef)();return Object(s.useEffect)((function(){var e=h.current.getBoundingClientRect().height,a=p.current.getBoundingClientRect().height;m(Math.max(e,a))}),[a.question,a.answer,a.options]),n.a.createElement("div",{className:"card ".concat(i?"flip":""),style:{height:d}},n.a.createElement("div",{className:"front",style:{height:d+6},ref:h},a.question,n.a.createElement("div",{className:"flashcard-options"},a.options.map((function(e){return n.a.createElement("div",{className:"flashcard-option",key:e},n.a.createElement("button",{className:"btn option-btn btn-primary",onClick:function(){return t={option:e},void(a.answer===t.option?alert("yep, that's correct"):alert("nope, that's incorrect"));var t}},e))}))),n.a.createElement("button",{className:"btn view-btn btn-success ".concat(i?"flip":""),onClick:function(){return r(!i)}},"see answer")),n.a.createElement("div",{className:"back",onClick:function(){return r(!i)},style:{height:d+6},ref:p},a.answer))}function u(e,a){var t=e.flashcards,s=a.correctAnswers;return n.a.createElement("div",{className:"card-grid"},t.map((function(e){return n.a.createElement(l,{flashcard:e,key:e.id,correctAnswers:s})})))}t(12);var d=[{id:2,name:"SageMaker Algorithms: Purpose (e.g. image classification)"},{id:1,name:"SageMaker Algorithms: Model Type (e.g. CNN)"},{id:4,name:"General Questions"},{id:3,name:"AWS tools/services purpose"}],m=[],h=[{name:"Linear Learner",modelType:"linear regression",purpose:"regression or classification",processor:"cpu"},{name:"XGboost",modelType:"decision tree(s)",purpose:"regression or classification",processor:"cpu"},{name:"Seq2Seq",modelType:"RNNs and CNNs with attention",purpose:"translation, summarization, speech to text",processor:"gpu"},{name:"DeepAR",modelType:"RNN",purpose:"forecast one dimensional time series",processor:"cpu or gpu"},{name:"BlazingText",modelType:"word2vec and text classification",purpose:"text classification",processor:"cpu or gpu"},{name:"Object2Vec",modelType:"object2vec",purpose:"determine how similar objects are to each other",processor:"cpu or gpu"},{name:"Object Detection",modelType:"CNN",purpose:"identify object in image and identify bounding boxes",processor:"gpu"},{name:"Image Classification",modelType:"ResNet CNN",purpose:"assign labels to image",processor:"gpu"},{name:"Semantic Segmentation",modelType:"MXNet Gluon and Gluon CV",purpose:"pixel level object classification",processor:"gpu"},{name:"Random Cut Forest",modelType:"decision tree(s)",purpose:"anomaly detection",processor:"cpu"},{name:"Neural Topic Model",modelType:"neural topic model",purpose:"document topic modelling/classification",processor:"gpu"},{name:"LDA: Latent Dirichlet Allocation",modelType:"latent dirichlet allocation",purpose:"document topic modelling/classification",processor:"gpu"},{name:"K-Nearest-Neighbors",modelType:"KNN",purpose:"regression or classification",processor:"cpu or gpu"},{name:"K-Means Clustering",modelType:"k-Means",purpose:"unsupervised clustering",processor:"cpu"},{name:"Principal Component Analysis (PCA)",modelType:"principal component analysis",purpose:"dimensionality reduction",processor:"cpu"},{name:"Factorization Machines",modelType:"factorization machines",purpose:"recommender systems",processor:"cpu or gpu"},{name:"IP insights",modelType:"CNN",purpose:"finding fishy behaviour in your weblogs",processor:"cpu or gpu"},{name:"Reinforcement Learning",modelType:"Q-learning",purpose:"learning by assigning rewards/penalties for states in the system",processor:"cpu or gpu"}],p=[{name:"S3",purpose:"Amazon S3 allows people to store objects (files) in 'buckets' (directories). Buckets must have a globally unique name. Objects (files) have a Key. The key is the full path"},{name:"Kinesis",purpose:"Kinesis is a managed alternative to Apache Kafka. Great for application logs, metrics, IoT, clickstreams. Great for \u201creal-time\u201d big data"},{name:"Glue ETL",purpose:"Transform data, Clean Data, Enrich Data (before doing analysis).  Target can be S3, JDBC (RDS, Redshift), or in Glue Data Catalog. Jobs are run on a serverless Spark platform"},{name:"Glue Data Catalogue",purpose:"Metadata repository for all your tables. Automated Schema Inference. Schemas are versioned"},{name:"DynamoDB",purpose:"Amazon DynamoDB is a fully managed proprietary NoSQL database service that supports key-value and document data structures"},{name:"AWS Data Pipeline",purpose:"Process and move data between different AWS compute and storage services such as Amazon S3, Amazon RDS, Amazon DynamoDB, and Amazon EMR."},{name:"AWS Batch",purpose:"Run batch jobs as Docker images. Dynamic provisioning of the instances (EC2 & Spot Instances)"},{name:"AWS DMS",purpose:"Database Migration Service helps you migrate databases to AWS quickly and securely. The source database remains fully operational during the migration, minimizing downtime to applications that rely on the database."},{name:"Step Functions",purpose:"Serverless function orchestrator that makes it easy to sequence AWS Lambda functions and multiple AWS services into business-critical applications."},{name:"Polly",purpose:"converts text into spoken audio. It allows developers to create speech-enabled applications and products."},{name:"Rekognition",purpose:"Fast and accurate face search, allowing you to identify a person in a photo or video"},{name:"Transcribe",purpose:"Speech-to-text. Automatic speech recognition (ASR)"},{name:"Lex",purpose:"Chatbot"},{name:"EMR",purpose:"Fully managed Hadoop ecosystem"},{name:"Athena",purpose:"Query data on S3."},{name:"Data Pipeline",purpose:"AWS Data Pipeline is a cloud-based data workflow service that helps you process and move data between different AWS services and on-premise data sources."},{name:"Redshift",purpose:"Data Warehouse cluster. Congregates data from other sources"},{name:"Redshift Spectrum",purpose:"Query your Redshift data. you can use tools like quicksight to analyse, visualize"},{name:"Comprehend",purpose:"Natural language processing (NLP) service that uses machine learning to find insights and relationships in text. (such as sentiment analysis)"},{name:"CloudTrail",purpose:"CloudTrail records actions from users, roles, and services within SageMaker. Audit trail of what every one did"},{name:"CloudWatch",purpose:"Cloud watch monitoring log data, issues alarms when things go wrong."},{name:"Elastic Inference",purpose:"Accelerated deep learning inference more cost effectively than dedicated GPU instance. When you deploy your inference model, will deploy to a CPU instance, but also specify an elastic inference accelerator along side with it. Can excelerate notebooks as well. Only works with deep learning. (Tensorflow/MXnet). Works with Image classification, Object detection build in algorithms."},{name:"Neo",purpose:"Neo makes it easy to prepare your model for deployment on virtually any hardware platforms"},{name:"IoT green grass",purpose:" Internet of Things (IoT) edge runtime and cloud service that helps you build, deploy, and manage device software"},{name:"Ground Truth",purpose:"fully managed data labeling service that makes it easy to build highly accurate training datasets for machine learning"},{name:"Kinesis Firehose",purpose:"reliably load, transform, and deliver streaming datastreaming data into data lakes, data stores, and analytics services."},{name:"Kinesis Producer Library (KPL)",purpose:"Easy to use library that allows you to write to a Kinesis data stream"},{name:"Kinesis Client Library",purpose:"Integrates direclty with KPL for consumer applications to consume and process data from Kinesis data stream"},{name:"Kinesis API (AWS SDK)",purpose:"Used for low level API operations to send records to a Kinesis data stream"},{name:"texttract",purpose:"Amazon Textract is a fully managed machine learning service that automatically extracts printed text, handwriting, and other data from scanned documents."},{name:"VPC flow logs",purpose:"monitor all traffic going in and out of your VPC containing your deployed SageMaker model."},{name:"Amazon Forecast",purpose:"Time series forcasting."},{name:"Amazon Personalize",purpose:"Recommendation Engine as a service."},{name:"Fargate",purpose:""}],f=["Standard deviation (represented by the symbol sigma, \u03c3 ) shows how much variation or dispersion exists from the average (mean), or expected value. More precisely, it is a measure of the average distance between the values of the data in the set and the mean.","Delete records with missing values, Mean imputation, KNN: Find K \u201cnearest\u201d (most similar) rows and average their values, Deep Learning: Build a machine learning model to impute data for your machine learning model, Regression: Find linear or non-linear relationships between the missing feature and other features, Just Get More Data","Oversampling - duplicate samples from the minority class, Undersampling - instead of creating more positive samples, remove negative ones, Throwing data away is usually not the right answer, SMOTE (Synthetic Minority Over-sampling TEchnique) - Artificially generate new samples of the minority class using nearest neighbors, Adjusting thresholds","Stands for Term Frequency and Inverse Document Frequency. Term Frequency measures how often a word occurs in a document. Document Frequency is how often a word occurs in an entire set of documents. TF-IDF measures the relevancy of a word in a document. Vector of TF-IDF = (number of documents, number of unique n-grams)","Regularization techniques are intended to prevent overfitting. Some techniques are Dropout (removing neurons from some layers) and Early Stopping -  Early stopping rules provide guidance as to how many iterations can be run before the learner begins to over-fit","R-squared is a statistical measure of how close the data are to the fitted regression line. It is also known as the coefficient of determination, or the coefficient of multiple determination for multiple regression.","L1 and L2 are two loss functions in machine learning which are used to minimize the error. L1 Loss function stands for Least Absolute Deviations. Also known as LAD. L2 Loss function stands for Least Square Errors. Also known as LS.","(True Positives / True Positives + False Negatives) AKA Sensitivity, True Positive rate, Completeness. Percent of positives rightly predicted, good choice of metric when you care a lot about false negatives","(True Positives / True Positives + False Positives) AKA Correct Positives. Percent of relevant results, Good choice of metric when you care a lot about false positives","confusion matrix is...","The easy way to determine what the tf-idf in vectorized format is, is by using the following: (number of documents, number of unique n-grams)","1 - 500","24 hours to 7 days","Kinesis API"],g=[{question:"What is standard deviation?",answer:f[0]},{question:"What are some common methods to deal with missing values in a dataset",answer:f[1]},{question:"How can you deal with unbalanced data - large discrepancy between 'positive' and 'negative' cases : as in fraud detection",answer:f[2]},{question:"What is TF-IDF",answer:f[3]},{question:" What is regularization? And what are some techniques?",answer:f[4]},{question:"what is R2 in machine learning?",answer:f[5]},{question:"what are L1 and L2 in machine learning?",answer:f[6]},{question:"what is Recall?",answer:f[7]},{question:"what is Precision?",answer:f[8]},{question:"what is Boosting?",answer:"Boosting is an ensemble meta-algorithm for primarily reducing bias, weaker models are trained in sequence to develop a stronger model. Boosting increases accuracy"},{question:"what is Bagging?",answer:"Boosting is an ensemble meta-algorithm. multiple models are trained in parallel on sample sets of the data, and vote on the best outcome. Baggin avoids overfitting."},{question:"How do you calculate the TF-IDF matrix for a given set of documents?",answer:f[10]},{question:"What is the default shard limit for kinesis data streams?",answer:f[11]},{question:"What is retention perdiod for data within a shard of a Kinesis data stream?",answer:f[12]},{question:"If speed of data transer is of utmost important, which is better KPL or Kinesis API?",answer:f[13]},{question:"What is standardization",answer:"Standardization is a scaling technique where the values are centered around the mean with a unit standard deviation. This means that the mean of the attribute becomes zero and the resultant distribution has a unit standard deviation."},{question:"What is normalization",answer:"scaling technique where values are scaled to be between zero and one. It is also known as Min-Max scaling."},{question:"What controls outside access to VPC",answer:"NAT or internet gateway"},{question:"How long are logs available in CloudTrail's event history",answer:"By default the last 90 days are visible in the CloudTrail event history."},{question:"How long is Cloudwatch data available",answer:"Maximum 15 months, the most recent 2 weeks are visible in the console."},{question:"How do you calculate production varient weights",answer:"The traffic to a production variant is determined by the ratio of the VariantWeight to the sum of all VariantWeights."},{question:"Why do VPC endpoints increase security and lower cost",answer:"Because the request no longer has to go out of the VPC into the public internet to access public services like S3 and Sagemaker, and can access them directly."},{question:"What are ways to deal with underfitting",answer:"Add more variables, more data, or train longer."},{question:"What are ways to deal with overfitting",answer:"Add more data, early stopping, regularization, boosting or bagging, remove unimportant features (Feature selection, you could use PCA), add noise."},{question:"What is AUC (Area under curve)",answer:"A performance across all possible classification thresholds. A model whose predictions are 100% wrong has an AUC of 0.0; one whose predictions are 100% correct has an AUC of 1.0."},{question:"What does a negative residual distribution tell you?",answer:"That my predicted value was higher than the actual value."},{question:"What does a positive residual distribution tell you?",answer:"That my predicted value was lower than the actual value."},{question:"What is RMSE",answer:"Root Means Square Error - It is the distance between our predicted value and the actual value on a cartesian graph. You want this to be as low as possible."},{question:"What are Type I errors",answer:"False Positives"},{question:"What are Type II errors",answer:"False Negatives"},{question:"After multiple training runs, you notice that the the loss function settles on different but similar values. You believe that there is potential to improve the model through adjusting hyperparameters. What might you try next?",answer:"Decrease the learning rate"},{question:"High bias equates to?",answer:"Overfitting"},{question:"High variance equates to?",answer:"Underfitting"},{question:"What visualization can be used to show all features and the correlation they have with all other features?",answer:"Heatmap"},{question:"How can you ensure encryption at rest is achieved when developing models in sagemaker notebooks",answer:"Create a customer managed key in KMS and use it when creating your SageMaker Notebook instance"},{question:"What format does blazing text expect for text transformation in file mode",answer:"A single preprocessed text file with space-separated tokens where the training file should contain a training sentence per line along with the labels. Labels are words that are prefixed by the string label."},{question:"If you want each data scientist to work in their own notebook, how do you controll access",answer:"Attach an IAM policy to the Data Scientists' IAM users that allows access to their personal notebook instances only."},{question:"What are the important step(s) to pre-process the text in NLP based projects?",answer:"Word standardization (removing things like acronyms, hashtags with attached words, colloquial slang), stemming (stripping the suffixes (\u201cing\u201d, \u201cly\u201d, \u201ces\u201d, \u201cs\u201d etc) from a word) and stop word removal (words that have no meaning in the text (am/i/are))"},{question:"How could data scientists import certain key libraries from the Internet into their notebooks if they've been restricted from internet access.",answer:"Create a NAT gateway within the Notebook VPC and associated default route to the NAT gateway."},{question:"Creating an S3 VPC Endpoint in your VPC will have what 2 impacts",answer:"increased security, decreased cost."},{question:"What type of models are less sensitive to unbalanced scaling among features",answer:"decision trees."},{question:"Regarding security, what falls into the category of visibility",answer:"VPC endpoints, Network Access Control Lists (NACL), and Security Groups"},{question:"Regarding security, what falls into the category of authentication",answer:"Identity and Access Managament (IAM)"},{question:"Regarding security, what falls into the category of Access Control",answer:"Key Management Service (KMS)"},{question:"What do VPC endpoints do?",answer:"Allow acces to publicly available AWS services within the VPC. (without going out into the public internet. May also be referred to as PrivateLink."},{question:"Some sagemaker actions like create model require a notebook user to pass in an IAM role so that sagemaker can assume that role to perform those actions.",answer:"This was a statement not a question"},{question:"What is an example of encryption at rest?",answer:"You can configure S3 to use S3-KMS encryption keys or use your own KMS encryption keys"},{question:"What is an example of encryption in transit?",answer:"Use Certificate Manager with CloudFront to provide TLS(SSL) for a custom domain."},{question:"What is the difference between a data lake and a data warehouse?",answer:"A data lake is a vast pool of raw data, the purpose for which is not yet defined. A data warehouse is a repository for structured, filtered data that has already been processed for a specific purpose."},{question:"What are the 2 modes of BlazingText?",answer:"WordToVec (unsupervised): Used for machine translation, sentiment analysis , and Text Classification (supervised): predict labels for a sentence, useful for search."},{question:"How do you calculate the F1 score",answer:"2 * (precision * recall/precision + recall)"},{question:"What is the effect of a too high or too low learning rate?",answer:"A learning rate that is too large can cause the model to converge too quickly to a suboptimal solution, whereas a learning rate that is too small can cause the process to get stuck."},{question:"What is the required format for factorization machines?",answer:"the factorization machines algorithm currently supports only the recordIO-protobuf format with Float32 tensors. CSV is not a good choice due to sparse data."},{question:"What are XGboost hyperparameters your could adjust that would prevent overfitting",answer:"Subsample"},{question:"Which is a valid approach for determining the optimal value of k in k-Means clustering?",answer:"The elbow method which is used to determine the optimal value of K to perform the K-Means Clustering Algorithm."},{question:"What is the possible effect of too large a batch size in a neural network?",answer:"Can cause training to get stuck in local minima"},{question:"How could you de-duplicate records?",answer:"Use Glue's FindMatches ML Tranform to remove duplicates"},{question:"Which is a viable option for connecting the S3 data to MapReduce on EMR?",answer:"Use EMRFS to connect Map Reduce to S3 using the s3:// prefix"},{question:"You are trying to classify a number of items based on different features into one of 6 groups (books, electronics, movies, etc.) based on features. Which algorithm would be best suited for this type of problem?",answer:"Use XGBoost with objective set to multi:softmax"},{question:"Why not use mean imputation if a data set has outliers?",answer:"This will skew the regression line away from the non-outliers. use median imputation instead."},{question:"What settings allow you to encrypt AWS GLue jobs?",answer:""},{question:"How should you deal with columns that have a majority missing values?",answer:"Remove them."},{question:"what is the max object size in S3?",answer:"5 TerraBytes (TB)"},{question:"What file formats are supported in S3?",answer:"Any format"},{question:"What do you use to move to different tiers in S3?",answer:"Lifecycle rules"},{question:"What are ways to encrypt data in S3?",answer:"SSE-S3 - Key managed by S3, and SSE-KMS, key managend in Key Management Service (KMS), this gives more control, better security, and audit trail."},{question:"How many availability zones is Kinesis data replicated to?",answer:"3"},{question:"What is the maximum size of data records going into Kinesis data streams?",answer:"1 MB"},{question:"What is the ingestion limit from the producer for Kinesis Data Streams?",answer:"1MB/s or 1000 messages/s per shard."},{question:"What is the ingestion limit for the consumer for Kinesis Data Streams?",answer:"2MB/s or % API calls/s per shard."},{question:"What is the latency of Kinesis Data Firehouse?",answer:"60 seconds minimum"},{question:"What are the destination stores for Kinesis Firehose?",answer:"S3, Redshift, ElasticSearch, Splunk"},{question:"What data format conversions can Kinesis Data Fireshose perform?",answer:"CSV/JSON to Parquet/ORC (S3 only, using a GLUE table schema), or any trasnformation through Lambda. It also support compression to S3."},{question:"How do you move data from S3 to Redshift?",answer:"COPY command"},{question:"What are 2 possible sources for Kinesis data firehose?",answer:"a PUT from other sources, and Kinesis data stream."},{question:"What are sources for Kinesis Data Anlaytics?",answer:"Kinesis data Streams, or Kinesis Data Firehose."},{question:"What are some outpuit destinations for Kinesis Data Anlaytics?",answer:"Kinesis data Streams, Kinesis Data Firehose, Lambda. Cannot go directlty to S3"},{question:"What are the use cases for Kinesis Analytics",answer:"Streaming ETL, real-time metrics, responsive analytics."},{question:"What are 2 Machine Learning tasks you can do with Kinesis Analytics?",answer:"Random Cut Forest (anomaly detection, only with recent history) and Hotspots (detect dense areas)"},{question:"How long is the data retention for Kinesis Video Streams?",answer:"1 hour to 10 years"},{question:"What is the use case for AWS batch",answer:"Non ETL-related batch jobs, use AWS batch. GLue is better for ETL jobs."},{question:"",answer:""},{question:"",answer:""}],w=["linear regression","logistic regression","decision tree(s)","multiple regression","CNN","ResNet CNN","RNN","RNNs and CNNs with attention","MXNet Gluon and Gluon CV","Q-learning","neural topic model","latent dirichlet allocation","factorization machines","KNN","k-Means","principal component analysis","word2vec and text classification","object2vec","none of the above"],y=["regression","classification","regression or classification","translation, summarization, speech to text","text classification","determine how similar objects are to each other","identify object in image and identify bounding boxes","assign labels to image","pixel level object classification","anomaly detection","document topic modelling/classification","unsupervised clustering","dimensionality reduction","recommender systems","finding fishy behaviour in your weblogs","learning by assigning rewards/penalties for states in the system"];function b(e){for(var a=e.length-1;a>0;a--){var t=Math.floor(Math.random()*(a+1)),s=[e[t],e[a]];e[a]=s[0],e[t]=s[1]}return e}function v(e){return"What is the purpose of "+e+"?"}function q(e,a,t){return function(e,a){return e.map((function(e){return[e,Math.random()]})).sort((function(e,a){return e[1]<a[1]?-1:1})).slice(0,a).map((function(e){return e[0]}))}(e,t).filter((function(e){return e!==a}))}var S=function(){var e=Object(s.useState)([]),a=Object(c.a)(e,2),t=a[0],o=a[1],i=Object(s.useState)([]),l=Object(c.a)(i,2),S=l[0],A=l[1],T=Object(s.useState)([]),k=Object(c.a)(T,2),W=k[0],C=k[1],N=Object(s.useState)([]),M=Object(c.a)(N,2),E=M[0],K=(M[1],Object(s.useState)(W.length+E.length)),P=(Object(c.a)(K,1)[0],Object(s.useRef)());function D(e){var a=document.createElement("textarea");return a.innerHTML=e,a.value}return Object(s.useEffect)((function(){A(d)}),[]),n.a.createElement(n.a.Fragment,null,n.a.createElement("div",{id:"header"},n.a.createElement("h2",null,"AWS ML Cert Exam Prep")),n.a.createElement("form",{id:"myForm",className:"form-header",onChange:function(e){e.preventDefault(),m=[],h=b(h),g=b(g),p=b(p),h.forEach((function(e){var a;m.push({categoryId:1,question:(a=e.name,"What type of model/algorithm does "+a+" implement?"),correct_answer:e.modelType,incorrect_answers:q(w,e.modelType,7)},{categoryId:2,question:v(e.name),correct_answer:e.purpose,incorrect_answers:q(y,e.purpose,7)})})),g.forEach((function(e){m.push({categoryId:4,question:e.question,hide:!0,correct_answer:e.answer,incorrect_answers:q(f,e.answer,7)})})),p.forEach((function(e){m.push({categoryId:3,question:e.name,hide:!0,correct_answer:e.purpose,incorrect_answers:[]})}));var a=m.filter((function(e){return e.categoryId===parseInt(P.current.value)}));o(a.map((function(e,a){var t=D(e.correct_answer),s=[];return s=e.hide?[]:[].concat(Object(r.a)(e.incorrect_answers.map((function(e){return D(e)}))),[t]),{id:"".concat(a,"-").concat(Date.now()),question:D(e.question),answer:t,options:s.sort((function(){return Math.random()-.5}))}})))}},n.a.createElement("div",{className:"form-group"},n.a.createElement("label",{htmlFor:"category"},"Category"),n.a.createElement("select",{id:"category",ref:P},n.a.createElement("option",{value:"choose a category",disabled:!0,selected:!0},"Choose a category..."),S.map((function(e){return n.a.createElement("option",{value:e.id,key:e.id},e.name)}))))),n.a.createElement("div",{className:"container"},n.a.createElement(u,{flashcards:t,correctAnswers:W,setCorrectAnswer:C})))};i.a.render(n.a.createElement(n.a.StrictMode,null,n.a.createElement(S,null)),document.getElementById("root"))},7:function(e,a,t){e.exports=t(13)}},[[7,1,2]]]);
//# sourceMappingURL=main.2b48d7d3.chunk.js.map